Guide to the Juliette Phifer Burstermann Collection 1948-1974 MS 000
Eastern Connecticut State University, Publisher
Juliette Phifer Burstermann Collection1948-1974
MS 000
3 linear feet (3 boxes)
Eastern Connecticut State University
Burstermann, Juliette Phifer.
The papers of an Assistant Professor and Professor at Willimantic State College/Eastern Connecticut State College
Provenance
The Burstermann Collection was received by the Archives during the 2001 Academic Year. The material was donated by former ECSU Alumna/Faculty/Administrator, Margaret S. Wilson. Additional information was provided by several other departments on the ECSU campus.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
Juliette Virginia Phifer was born in Charlotte, North Carolina on January 3, 1905. Following her graduation in 1928 from Slater State Normal School in Winston-Salem, NC, Juliette pursued an education in Elementary Education at the Winston-Salem Teachers College. She received a Bachelor of Science degree from that institution in 1929. During those years (the time line is not clear) Ms. Phifer taught elementary school for seven years--teaching in each of the seven grades within the school. She received her Master of Arts in Education in 1933 from the Teachers College of Columbia University in NY. From 1933 to 1934, Juliette taught at the Newbold Training School, which was associated with the State Teachers College in Fayetteville, NC. In 1934-1935, she was on leave from the Fayetteville Teachers College and was the State Supervisor of Adult Education at the North Carolina, USA Federal Emergency Relief Program. The following year, she returned to the Newbold Training School as the principal and remained there until 1946. Meanwhile in 1942, Ms. Burstermann embarked on her quest to obtain a doctoral degree in education, and commenced her studies at New York University. She completed all of the requirements and obtained the degree in 1948. That same year she was hired as an Assistant Professor at Willimantic State Teachers College, and held that designation until 1958. In 1959 she was promoted to the rank of full professor and remained at ECSC until her retirement in 1974. Juliette, the first African-American faculty member at this institution, was married in New York to Louis C. Burstermann in 1952 or 1953.
Scope and Content Note
The Burstermann Collection is a history of Juliette P. Burstermann's life at Eastern Connecticut State University, commencing in August of 1948 and continuing through her retirement 1974. The collection includes materials relating to her involvement with numerous outside organizations and committees during that same period as well as information related to her post-retirement activities from 1975-1992.
SERIES DESCRIPTION:
Series I: Awards/Memberships/Certificates
The items in this category relate to both Dr. Burstermann's personal and professional involvement in various organizations, as well as awards she received including Delta Gamma Kappa Society, AAUW, Connecticut Division, Association for Arts in Childhood and Quality of Life Executive Committee.
Series II: Conferences/Programs
The material in this series generally relates to Dr. Burstermann's professional involvement in various organizations including "Modern Math", Head Start Training and WCCI World Conference on Education.
Series III: Correspondence
The correspondence in this series is both personal and professional, relating to various apsects of Dr. Burstermann's activities while at Eastern.
Series IV: Curriculum
This part of the collection contains syllabi and course descriptions as prepared by Dr. Burstermann.
Series V: Personal
This series contains personal information about her life including transcripts, hiring confirmation, promotion material as well as biographical information.
Series VI: Publications
The items in this series include various types of printed material which were written by Dr. Burstermann or saved among her papers.
Series VII: Photographs
The photographs in this collection are a pictorial history of Dr. Burstermann's life as an educator dating from the 1940s to the 1980s.
Series VIII: Realia
This series includes a 1972 portrait-style photograph of Dr. Bursterman; two copies of Education for Peace a book in which she wrote Part I of Chapter 4 (one signed; one personalized to Margaret and William Wilson); a video-taped interview with Dr. Burstermann dated April 1989 and 4 ribboned name tags from various conventions.
Arrangement
The files are grouped into 8 series:
Series I: Awards/Memberships/Certificates
Series II: Conferences/Programs
Series III: Correspondence
Series IV: Curriculum
Series V: Personal
Series VI: Publications
Series VII: Photographs
Series VIII: Realia
Access Points
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Publications.; Photographs.; Administrative Records.; Press releases.; School Records.; Fliers. [printed matter]; Manuscripts.; Scrap-Books.; Interviews.
Related Material
The University Archives has a substantial collection of University Archives material and also houses the Connecticut Studies Collection. For more detailed information on these collections please contact the staff member at the reference desk.
Container List
[The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection.]
- Series I - Awards/Memberships/Certificates
  - Transcript-Winston-Salem Teachers' College, 1939; , 1948 (Box 1, Item 1)
  - Transcript-NYU School of Education, 1941-1942 (Box 1, Item 2)
  - Contract-WA. Natl. Ins. Company- Joint Faculty Assc./WSTC, Feb 11, 1953 (Box 1, Item 3)
  - Invoice-Ferncliff, Jun 30, 1964 (Box 1, Item 4)
  - Willimantic District Mental Health Assc., 1964-1965 (Box 1, Item 5)
  - Membership List- Inst. For Supervisors and Curriculum Leaders, Jul 22, 1965 (Box 1, Item 6)
  - Delta Kappa Gamma Society, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Item 7)
  - Certificate of Completion-Inst. For Teachers of Disadvantaged Youth, Aug 9, 1968 (Box 1, Item 8)
  - Membership List-CT Planning Committee - Conference-Children/Youth, 1970 (Box 1, Item 9)
  - Certificate of Recognition-UConn Labor Ed. Center, Jun 1970 (Box 1, Item 10)
  - AAUW- CT Division, Jun 1970 (Box 1, Item 11)
  - All College Leadership Award-ECSC, Apr 10, 1972 (Box 1, Item 12)
  - List-Elections and Appointments, Apr 12, 1972 (Box 1, Item 13)
  - Congratulations-Honor Key- Kappa Delta Pi, May 3, 1972 (Box 1, Item 14)
  - Citation-Service to ECSC, May 3, 1972 (Box 1, Item 15)
  - Retirement Card from Colleagues, 1973 (Box 1, Item 16)
  - Certificate-Winston-Salem University- 50th Anniversary of Graduation, May 21, 1973 (Box 1, Item 17)
  - Invitation-Dinner Honoring Retirees, Dec 11, 1973 (Box 1, Item 18)
  - Limerick composed by President Webb-Retirement, Dec 11, 1973 (Box 1, Item 19)
  - Distinguished Service Award - Mental Health Assc. Of CT, Oct 29, 1974 (Box 1, Item 20)
  - Cert. Achievement of the Community Service Society, Sep 1976 (Box 1, Item 21)
  - List-Awards and Citations, Apr 25, 1977 (Box 1, Item 22)
  - Program/Greetings-10th Commemorative IBC Congress-Closing Banquet, Jul 16, 1983 (Box 1, Item 23)
  - Certificate-Golden Ram Society- Salem-Winston University, 1989 (Box 1, Item 24)
  - Association for Arts in Childhood, undated (Box 1, Item 25)
  - List-Community Services, undated (Box 1, Item 26)
  - Membership-Quality of Life Executive Committee, undated (Box 1, Item 27)
  - Action Auction Cert. of Appreciation, undated (Box 1, Item 28)
  - Fellowship & Good Cheer Cerificate, undated (Box 1, Item 29)
- Series II - Conferences/Programs
  - Rhythms-Dance Review, May 21, 1952 (Box 1, Item 30)
  - In-Service Program-"Modern Math", May 1962 (Box 1, Item 31)
  - "Head Start Training"- Coppin State College, Jun 21, 1965-Jun 26, 1965 (Box 1, Item 32)
  - NDEA Summer Institute, Jul 1, 1968-Aug 8, 1968 (Box 1, Item 33)
  - Quality of Life (1 of 2), 1970s (Box 1, Item 34)
  - Quality of Life (2 of 2), 1970s (Box 1, Item 35)
  - ACSD-Asilomar, CA, Mar 5, 1970-Mar 14, 1970 (Box 1, Item 36)
  - CSEA 29th Annual Convention, Sep 24, 1970-Sep 26, 1970 (Box 1, Item 37)
  - CSEA 30th Annual Convention, Sep 23, 1971-Sep 25, 1971 (Box 1, Item 38)
  - Mental Health Association of CT, Dec 1973 (Box 1, Item 39)
  - WCCI World Conference on Education, Aug 14, 1977-Aug 24, 1977 (Box 1, Item 40)
- Series III - Correspondence
  - Outgoing
    - Curriculum Coordinator-WSTC, Aug 27, 1948 (Box 1, Item 41)
    - NC Teachers' & State Employees Retirement System, 1950s-1960s (Box 1, Item 42)
    - J. Eugene Smith, 1953 (Box 1, Item 43)
    - Jane Tuitt-Assc. Dean-College of the Virgin Islands, Jan 1968 (Box 1, Item 44)
    - Harold Howe II-Commissioner on Education, May 28, 1968 (Box 1, Item 45)
    - Department of H.E.W.-Washington D.C., Jul 1968-Aug 1968 (Box 1, Item 46)
    - Members of Divisional Council- College of the Virgin Islands, Aug 9, 1968 (Box 1, Item 47)
    - Department of Elementary Edu.- Change in dept. Leadership, Jan 1, 1971 (Box 1, Item 48)
    - Virginia Surowiec-CT State Teachers' Retirement Board, Jan 1971-Nov 1973 (Box 1, Item 49)
    - Dean Reilen-ECSC, Aug 1972 (Box 1, Item 50)
    - World Law Fund, Apr 1972-Oct 1973 (Box 1, Item 51)
    - Governor Meskill, 1972-1974 (Box 1, Item 52)
    - Isabella Wade, Mar 9, 1973 (Box 1, Item 53)
    - Education Dept.-Indiana University, Mar 28, 1973 (Box 1, Item 54)
    - "Educational Leadership", Oct 14, 1973 (Box 1, Item 55)
    - Florence Stevens, Oct 14, 1973 (Box 1, Item 56)
    - Mrs. David Best, Oct 14, 1973 (Box 1, Item 57)
    - NAMH-Annual Meeting, Nov 27, 1973 (Box 1, Item 58)
    - Consulting Group-Division of Community Services, Jan 14, 1974 (Box 1, Item 59)
    - Assc. Retired Teachers of CT, May 5, 1975 (Box 1, Item 60)
    - University of N. Dakota-Commencement Address, Apr 1977-1978 (Box 1, Item 61)
    - President Jimmy Carter, Nov 8, 1980 (Box 1, Item 62)
    - President Webb, May 1982-Aug 1982 (Box 1, Item 63)
    - Peg Wilson, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Item 64)
  - Incoming
    - Columbia University-Negro Education Club, Nov 17, 1937 (Box 1, Item 65)
    - Eleanor Roosevelt Dinner, Dec 1937 (Box 1, Item 66)
    - Fayettville State Teachers' College, Jan 26, 1942 (Box 1, Item 67)
    - Department of Elementary School Principals, Jul 15, 1947 (Box 1, Item 68)
    - NYU-Article Publication Request, Jun 17, 1947 (Box 1, Item 69)
    - The Community Church-New York, Feb 20, 1948 (Box 1, Item 70)
    - New York University, Jul 1, 1948 (Box 1, Item 71)
    - President Smith, 1948; , 1957-1959 (Box 1, Item 72)
    - Curriculum Coordinator-State Teachers' College, Aug 26, 1948 (Box 1, Item 73)
    - National Urban League-Congratulatory Note, Nov 4, 1948 (Box 1, Item 74)
    - CT State Department of Education, 1948; , 1953 (Box 1, Item 75)
    - Michael Phelan-JPB Former Student, Oct 1949 (Box 1, Item 76)
    - State Teachers' Retirement Board, 1949-1972 (Box 1, Item 77)
    - Organization of American Studies, Mar 19, 1951 (Box 1, Item 78)
    - N.H. Cox-NC Teachers' and State Retirement System, Aug 1951-Mar 1959 (Box 1, Item 79)
    - Richard Coughlin-CT Department of Education, Jul 30, 1952 (Box 1, Item 80)
    - Marilyn Randall-Thank You/Congratulatory Note, May 21, 1953 (Box 1, Item 81)
    - Hampton Institute, Sep 14, 1953-Sep 17, 1953 (Box 1, Item 82)
    - Brooklyn College, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Item 83)
    - Delta Gamma Nu Sigma, Feb 17, 1958 (Box 1, Item 84)
    - Bruce Bradford/William Nolan, Feb 13, 1962 (Box 1, Item 85)
    - John Freudenstein, Apr 16, 1962 (Box 1, Item 86)
    - Buell Gallagher-City College of NY, Jan 17, 1966 (Box 1, Item 87)
    - Coppin State College, MD, Jun 27, 1967 (Box 1, Item 88)
    - US Commission on Education, Jun 4, 1968 (Box 1, Item 89)
    - Department of H.E.W., Jun 27, 1968 (Box 1, Item 90)
    - U. of Puerto Rico-College of Education, Aug 28, 1968 (Box 1, Item 91)
    - Jane Tuitt, Aug 1968 (Box 1, Item 92)
    - UConn-School of Education, Oct 29, 1968 (Box 1, Item 93)
    - AAUW, May 4, 1969 (Box 1, Item 94)
    - Governor John Dempsey, Mar 5, 1970 (Box 1, Item 95)
    - President Webb, Dec 1970-Jun 1977 (Box 1, Item 96)
    - Winston Salem State University-Alumni Association, May 21, 1971 (Box 1, Item 97)
    - President Webb-Sabbatic Leave, May 8, 1972 (Box 1, Item 98)
    - Institute for World Order, Apr 1972-Apr 1973 (Box 1, Item 99)
    - Department of Children and Youth, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Item 100)
    - Assoc. for Supervision and Curriculum Development, 1973 (Box 1, Item 101)
    - Women's International League for Peace and Freedom, 1973 (Box 1, Item 102)
    - Isabella Wade-Education for Peace, 1973 (Box 1, Item 103)
    - Regina Haddad, Mar 19, 1973 (Box 1, Item 104)
    - District of Union City, MO, Apr 17, 1973 (Box 1, Item 105)
    - Manitowoc, WI-Public Schools, Aug 1973 (Box 1, Item 106)
    - Florence Stevens, Sep 27, 1973 (Box 1, Item 107)
    - Board of Trustees-State Colleges, Nov 29, 1973 (Box 1, Item 108)
    - Governor-Virgin Islands, Apr 10, 1974 (Box 1, Item 109)
    - Education Commission of the States, Sep 20, 1974 (Box 1, Item 110)
    - Paul Nuttal, Nov 15, 1974 (Box 1, Item 111)
    - University of North Dakota, Mar 1977-Jan 1978 (Box 1, Item 112)
    - President Jimmy Carter, Nov 25, 1980 (Box 1, Item 113)
    - Representative James Coyne-PA, May 7, 1981 (Box 1, Item 114)
    - College of the Virgin Islands, Mar 12, 1982 (Box 1, Item 115)
    - Ralph Yulo-ECSU, May 31, 1984 (Box 1, Item 116)
    - International Congress on Arts & Communication, Jul 8, 1984 (Box 1, Item 117)
    - Michael Pernal-Fringe Benefits, Oct 30, 1990 (Box 1, Item 118)
    - Reverend and Mrs. Leonard Craine, undated (Box 1, Item 119)
- Series IV - Curriculum
  - Permission Slips-Field Trip to Slater Museum, Apr 11, 1955 (Box 1, Item 120)
  - Brooklyn College-Final Exam, 1958 (Box 1, Item 121)
  - Syllabi-Brooklyn College-"Intro. To Edu.", 1959-1960 (Box 1, Item 122)
  - Student Term Papers, 1967-1971 (Box 1, Item 123)
  - Course Descriptions (taught by JPB) Brooklyn College, undated (Box 1, Item 124)
  - Students' Creative Writing Projects, undated (Box 1, Item 125)
- Series V - Personal
  - Transcript-NYU, 1940-1942 (Box 1, Item 126)
  - Personnel Data, Aug 30, 1948 (Box 1, Item 127)
  - CT Dept. of Edu-Personnel Record Change Sheet, 1948-1959 (Box 1, Item 128)
  - Brooklyn College-Critique of Education Course, Mar 26, 1958 (Box 1, Item 129)
  - Biographical Sketch, ca. 1959 (Box 1, Item 130)
  - Biography by J. Eugene Smith, Sep 1, 1959 (Box 1, Item 131)
  - Biographical Information, [?1967] (Box 1, Item 132)
  - Reimbursement-Travel Expenses, Dec 1970 (Box 1, Item 133)
  - Resume, 1971 (Box 1, Item 134)
  - Obituary/Services, 1992 (Box 1, Item 135)
  - Biographical Document and Draft, undated (Box 1, Item 136)
- Series VI - Publications
  - Study of the Yearbooks of the American Association Of Teacher Colleges, 1922-1937 (Box 2, Item 1)
  - Remarks to Eleanor Roosevelt, 1937 (Box 2, Item 2)
  - Outline-Major Course for Teachers, Critics, Supervisors, & Administrators, 1937-1938 (Box 2, Item 3)
  - Term Paper-...Experiment w/ Cooperatives in Nova Scotia, Feb 1939 (Box 2, Item 4)
  - Record of Tests given in Guidance Lab, Oct 21, 1937-Dec 9, 1937 (Box 2, Item 5)
  - "Negro History Bulletin", Jun 1940 (Box 2, Item 6)
  - Examination Problems, Jul 1940 (Box 2, Item 7)
  - Course Outline, Aug 8, 1940 (Box 2, Item 8)
  - State-Wide Study of Teacher Education-North Carolina, 1940-1943 (Box 2, Item 9)
  - "Our 'No Failure' Program"-NYU Course, 1942 (Box 2, Item 10)
  - "My Own Diary"-NYU Course (1 of 2), Spring, 1942 (Box 2, Item 11)
  - "My Own Diary"-NYU Course (2 of 2), Spring, 1942 (Box 2, Item 12)
  - "School and Society"-Newbold School, Oct 1942 (Box 2, Item 13)
  - Report-Evaluation of "No Failure" Program- Newbold School, Sep 1943-Jan 1944 (Box 2, Item 14)
  - "Experiment with a Program of Continuous Growth", 1945 (Box 2, Item 15)
  - "Progressive Education", May 1945 (Box 2, Item 16)
  - Catalog-Fayettville State Teacher College, 1945-1946 (Box 2, Item 17)
  - Bibliographical References in "Current Problems...", undated (Box 2, Item 18)
  - Doctorate Thesis- Public Education in Haiti since 1934 (1 of 3), 1948 (Box 2, Item 19)
  - Doctorate Thesis- Public Education in Haiti since 1934 (2 of 3), 1948 (Box 2, Item 20)
  - Doctorate Thesis- Public Education in Haiti since 1934 (3 of 3), 1948 (Box 2, Item 21)
  - Newsletter-"Assoc. For Arts in Childhood", Mar 1948 (Box 2, Item 22)
  - New Release-JPB appointed Assoc. Professor-WSTC, Oct 29, 1948 (Box 2, Item 23)
  - Newspaper-Bridgeport Sunday Herald, Nov 28, 1948 (Box 2, Item 24)
  - Campus Lantern, Sep 30, 1953 (Box 2, Item 25)
  - Newspaper-St. Croix Auis, Oct 6, 1953 (Box 2, Item 26)
  - Newspaper-The Daily News, Virgin Islands, Feb 18, 1954 (Box 2, Item 27)
  - Newspaper-Journal and Guide, Jun 22, 1957 (Box 2, Item 28)
  - Newspaper-Pittsburgh Courier, Jun 22, 1957 (Box 2, Item 29)
  - Newspaper-The St. Croix Auis, Virgin Islands, Jul 1, 1957 (Box 2, Item 30)
  - News Release-9 Years as Assoc., 1957 (Box 2, Item 31)
  - "My Experiences in Cultural Integration at WSTC", 1958 (Box 2, Item 32)
  - Newspaper-"The Listener"-Monrovia, Liberia, Sep 12, 1959 (Box 2, Item 33)
  - Newspaper- The St. Croix Auis, Virgin Islands, Jun 2, 1959 (Box 2, Item 34)
  - Extension Program 2nd Semester Willimantic State College, 1959-1960 (Box 2, Item 35)
  - Report-"An Experiment with Cuisenaire Rods", Jun 11, 1962 (Box 2, Item 36)
  - Exams-History and Philosophy of Education, Spring 1962; , Spring 1964 (Box 2, Item 37)
  - Exams-History and Philosophy of Education, Fall 1966 (Box 2, Item 38)
  - Outline-"The Vocabulary of Philosophy", Spring 1965 (Box 2, Item 39)
  - Display, 1967-1977 (Box 2, Item 40)
  - Magazine-"The State Employee", 1968 (Box 2, Item 41)
  - Report-Final Technical Report- NDEA Summer Institute (1 of 2), Jul 1, 1968-Aug 9, 1968 (Box 2, Item 42)
  - Report-Final Technical Report- NDEA Summer Institute (2 of 2), Jul 1, 1968-Aug 9, 1968 (Box 2, Item 43)
  - ECSC Education in Crisis Series, Oct 25, 1968 (Box 2, Item 44)
  - Newspaper-Willimantic Chronicle, Oct 28, 1968 (Box 2, Item 45)
  - Newspaper-Hartford Courant, Jun 18, 1970 (Box 2, Item 46)
  - Newspaper-Norwich Bulletin, Jun 13, 1972 (Box 2, Item 47)
  - ASCD Yearbook Dedication, 1973 (Box 2, Item 48)
  - Participant List-ASCD Session-Peace Education, 1973 (Box 2, Item 49)
  - Newspaper-Peace, Feb 1973 (Box 2, Item 50)
  - Newspaper-Willimantic Chronicle Special College Edition, Aug 23, 1973 (Box 2, Item 51)
  - "Reflections", 1974 (Box 2, Item 52)
  - Newspaper-Willimantic Chronicle, Apr 28, 1977 (Box 2, Item 53)
  - Magazine-International Biographical Centre, 1977 (Box 2, Item 54)
  - ECSC Alumni News, Nov 1977 (Box 2, Item 55)
  - Winter Commencement Program-U of North Dakota, Dec 20, 1977 (Box 2, Item 56)
  - Newspaper-"The ADVANCE of Bucks County", Jan 5, 1984 (Box 2, Item 57)
  - Newspaper-"Courier Times", 1988 (Box 2, Item 58)
  - Memorial-Riverside Church, 1992 (Box 2, Item 59)
  - "New Century News", Winter 1992 (Box 2, Item 60)
  - Drafts-JPB's Works, undated (Box 2, Item 61)
  - Quality of Life-Minutes, undated (Box 2, Item 62)
  - Quality of Life-Notices/Agendas, undated (Box 2, Item 63)
  - Quality of Life-Reports and Recommendations, undated (Box 2, Item 64)
  - Newspaper Article-JPB as Guest Speaker, undated (Box 2, Item 65)
  - Newspaper Article-Speaker at Alpha Zeta Sygma, undated (Box 2, Item 66)
  - Outline for Speech-"Urbanization-Why the Inner City?", undated (Box 2, Item 67)
  - Postcard-Shafer Hall, undated (Box 2, Item 68)
  - "A Potential Embarrassing Moment Becomes a Pleasant Memory", undated (Box 2, Item 69)
  - Works (Author Unknown), undated (Box 2, Item 70)
  - Associate Professor- Newspaper Article, undated (Box 2, Item 71)
- Series VII - Photographs
  - Personal Photographs, undated (Box 2, Item 72)
  - WSTC Laboratory School, 1940s; , 1950s (Box 2, Item 73)
  - Newbold School, 1943-1944 (Box 2, Item 74)
  - Model School Willimantic postcards, 1948 (Box 2, Item 75)
  - Emergency Teacher Training Program, 1949 (Box 2, Item 76)
  - Robert Spillane, 1949-1950 (Box 2, Item 77)
  - Intensive Program for College Graduates, 1952; , 1953 (Box 2, Item 78)
  - AAUW Convention-Coretta Scott King Award, 1969 (Box 2, Item 79)
  - ASCD, 1970; , 1970 (Box 2, Item 80)
  - JBC Conference Denmark, 1973 (Box 2, Item 81)
  - Convention in Istanbul, Turkey, Aug 1977 (Box 2, Item 82)
  - JPB Observing Math Class-Newtown Friends School, PA, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Item 83)
  - Pennswood Village, Dec 1981 (Box 2, Item 84)
  - Ralph Yulo with daughter Julie Ann, 1984 (Box 2, Item 85)
  - 2nd Educational Exchange Program [20-31 March (no year)], undated (Box 2, Item 86)
  - Governor Meskill Signing Proclamation for "Quality of Life", undated (Box 2, Item 87)
  - "Investigating the Curriculum..." (Haiti?), undated (Box 2, Item 88)
  - Michael Gates-Former Student, undated (Box 2, Item 89)
  - Regional Study Tour-Puerto Rico, undated (Box 2, Item 90)
- Series VIII - Realia
  - Nametags & ribbons (CT State Employees Assoc.-2), 1970; , 1972 (Box 3, Item 1)
  - Nametags & ribbons (National Assoc. Mental Health), undated (Box 3, Item 2)
  - Nametags & ribbons (IBC, Pennsylvannia), undated (Box 3, Item 3)
  - Photograph of Juliette P. Burstermann (11x14, color), 1972 (Box 3, Item 4)
  - Education for Peace, Focus on Mankind (2 copies, signed), 1973 (Box 3, Item 5)
  - Interview with Juliette P. Burstermann (VHS), Apr 1989 (Box 3, Item 6)